<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on WorkflowFM Reasoner</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on WorkflowFM Reasoner</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 14:08:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 14:08:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/setup/</guid><description>Quick setup Clone the following repository: https://github.com/workflowfm/hol-light
1git clone https://github.com/workflowfm/hol-light.git Then make sure all the submodules are initialised and updated:
1git submodule update --init --recursive Manual setup Assuming an existing installation of HOL Light, you can setup the reasoner manually by installing the following libraries:
The Isabelle Light library. This also comes bundled with HOL Light by default. Additional HOL Light tools. This consists of useful snippets of code, libraries, and theorems.</description></item><item><title>Install HOL Light</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/hol-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 14:08:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/hol-light/</guid><description>You can install HOL Light by following its standard installation instructions.
We have included our own notes below in case they are helpful.
Specific tips for DICE users at the University of Edinburgh are included below.
Install OCaml OCaml 4.07.0 minimum is required. The easiest way to install this is through opam.
On DICE, opam can be compiled from source and installed locally. It is better to use a locally installed OCaml than the centrally available one.</description></item><item><title>Loading the reasoner</title><link>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/load/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 14:08:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://docs.workflowfm.com/workflowfm-reasoner/docs/install/load/</guid><description>Once you have HOL Light up and running, you can load the reasoner in console mode using the following command:
1loads (!hol_dir ^ &amp;#34;/workflowfm/make.console.ml&amp;#34;);; If you need to use the JSON mode, you can use this command instead:
1loads (!hol_dir ^ &amp;#34;/workflowfm/make.ml&amp;#34;);;</description></item></channel></rss>